

PROFILE

I have a passionate interest for the numerous elements and mechanisms that is influences the development of the global markets, currently and historically.

I can offer expertise within datascience, Business Intelligence, Advanced statistics, Financial Modelling. Forecasting and market research in equities, fixed-income, and commodity markets.

CONTACT

PHONE: +45 30132128

EMAIL: p.folmerdk@gmail.com

ADDRESS:

Sophiebreumsvej 1. 2. Sal. Lej. 29

ZIP: 5000 - Odense C

DENMARK

WILL RELOCATE NATIONALLY AND INTERNATIONALLY

PETER FOLMER

AN AMBITIOUS ECONOMICS & FINANCE GRADUATE

LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/PETER-FOLMER-B75933141

EDUCATION

Cand. Oecon. Finance

University of Southern Denmark

September 2018 - April 2021

<u>Courses:</u> Advanced Corporate Finance, Derivatives & Risk Management, Advanced Microeconomics, Econometrics, Dynamic Asset Allocation, Real Options, Financial Modelling, Asset Pricing

<u>Final Thesis:</u> Using deep-learning NLP models for analyzing corporate earnings-calls to predict abnormal returns in emerging market corporate bonds:

- Importing bond-data and transcripts via WRDS and Bloomberg
- Structuring, formatting, and cleaning texts and bond pricing data
- Constructing composite daily returns by grouping all firm level issues
- Designing reference portfolio
- Building a BERT NLP model

BSc. Economics and Business Administration – Business Management University of Southern Denmark

September 2015 – June 2018

<u>Selected courses:</u> Benchmarking, Mathematics, Microeconomics, Macroeconomics, Investments & Corporate finance, Management accounting, Financial accounting, Operations & supply-chain management, Business Law, Adv. Quantitative Analysis. Project Management.

<u>Bachelor Thesis:</u> In collaboration with energinet - "Implementation of Big Data in small and midsize companies".

KEY SKILLS

- Financial Markets Research
- Financial Planning
- Derivatives modelling Economics
- Fixed Income Research NLP
- Big Data Analytics Regex
- Data Science Python SQL
- Machine Learning TensorFlow
- VBA for Excel Stata API
- R Statistical Lanauage
- Business Intelligence Webscraping
- Analysis of unstructured data

LANGUAGES

Danish - Native

English - Fluent

German - Basic

Spanish - Basic

CODING & IT

Python - Advanced Level (Language of Choice)

- Data Science and statistics for financial applications
- Experience with AI and Machine Learning mainly for Natural Language Processing (NLP) using TensorFlow
- Importing data using API's and SQL queries via Python
- Working with Regex for analyzing and cleaning unstructured textual data

VBA for Excel - Experienced

- Financial modelling Developing Analytical Tools
- Automated data applications

Excel - Advanced Level

R - Advanced Level

Stata - Experienced

EXPERIENCE

Global Evolution A/S - Intern

September 2019 – January 2020

- Implementation of NLP model to analyze whether broad media sentiment can predict volatility in Sovereign bond markets for selected Emerging Market countries.
- Developing analytical tools in VBA and Python for supporting portfolio managers. As example, a tool in VBA to automatically import and benchmark daily performance of competing fixed income funds.

PETUA SG20 – Professional Fisherman, North Sea

February 2015 – August 2015

Vessel operation, onboard operations and navigation

XL-Byg Marstal A/S - Salesman

November 2010 – August 2014

- Sales, advising of b2c and b2b clients.
- Procurement, negotiating prices and terms with suppliers.
- Part-time: 2010-2013 / Full-time: 2013-2014

Ærø Maskiner & VVS A/S - Assistant

June 2006 - June 2011